<resources>
    <string name = "app_name">APNA UTTARAKHAND</string>
    <string name = "Dehradun">

        <b>Dehradun ::</b>
        \n\n\t\t Nested in the mountain ranges of the Himalaya, Dehradun is one of the oldest cities of India and is recently declared as the Provisional Capital of newly created Uttaranchal (Now Uttarakhand) State in the month of Nov/t’2000. Also known as the ‘Adobe of Drona/t’, Dehradun has always been an important center for Garhwal rulers which was captured by the British. The headquarters of many National Institutes and Organizations like ONGC, Survey Of India, Forest Research Institute, Indian Institute of Petroleum etc are located in the city. Some of the premier educational and Training Institutes like Indian Miltary Academy, RIMC(Rashtriya Indian Military College), Indira Gandhi National Forest Academy(IGNFA), Lal Bahadur Shahstri National Academy of Administration(LBSNAA)etc are also there in Dehradun. It is a favoured tourist destination as it attracts tourists, pilgrims and enthusiasts from various walks of life to its serene environs. Add to this the abundance of special Basmati rice, tea and leechi gardens which contribute in turning the city into a paradise.

        \n\n\t\t The district is named after its chief city Dehra Dun. Dehradun appears to be a collection of deras signifying a temporary abode or camp. During the reign of Aurangzeb, Ram Rai, Guru of the Udasi Sikhs on being ordered by the Mughal king to retire to the wilderness of the Dun, had pitched his tents here in what is now the Khurbura locality of the town and has also built a temple near Dhamawala. Around these two sites, grew up the town popularly known as Dehra. The term dun or doon means the low lands at the foot of a mountain range, and as the bulk of the district lies in such a terrain, it justified the dun part of the name.

        \n\n\t\t  Another derivation of the term dun is stated to be from Dronashram, hermitage of Guru Dronacharya of Mahabharata fame, who sojourned for a season in the village of Devara, situated near to Dehra to perform his devotions at a lonely spot.

        \n\n\t\t   District Boundaries and other Details

        \n\n\t\t  The district is situated in the north-west corner of the state.
        \t\t It is bounded on the north and to some distance in the north-west by the district of Uttarkashi,
        \t\t In the east by the district Tehri Garhwal and Pauri-Garhwal.
        \t\t  In the south by the district of Saharanpur(Uttar Pradesh) .
        \t\t At its southern tip touching the boundary of district Haridwar.
        \t\t Its western boundary adjoins the Sirmur(Nahan) district of Himachal Pradesh with the rivers Tons and Yamuna separating the two.
        \t\t Lies between 29 degrees 58′ and 31 degrees 2′ 30″ north latitudes and 77 degrees 34′ 45″ and 78 degrees 18′ 30″ east longitudes.
        \t\t Total area of the district is 3088 sq kms.
        \t\t Altitude is 640 mts.(2100 ft) above sea level .




    </string>
    <string name ="Champawat">
       <b> Champawat : KALI KUMAON</b>
\n\n\t\t Champawat district was formerly a part of almora district. In 1972, the part came under pithoragarh district. In 1997 september 15, champawat was declared an individual, independent district.

\n\n\t\t Champawat is valued in uttarakhand as the place of origin of culture and religion in uttarakhand region. The champawat land is considered to be the home of naga and kinnar described in hindu mythology. The region was ruled by khash kings in past. Historical pillars, monuments, manuscripts, archeological collections and folklores of the region are the evidences to its historical importance.  The manuscripts make it clear that katyur dynasty ruled the region in the past.

\n\n\t\t  Champawat district is one among 13 districts of uttarakhand state, india. Champawat district administrative head quarter is champawat. It is is located 266 km west towards state capital dehradun . Champawat district population is 259648 approx. It is 12 th largest district in the state by population.

\n\n\t\t  Champawat is located in the eastern kumaon division at state of uttarakhand. The region is bounded by nepal region on east, udham singh nagar district on south, nainital district on west and almora district on north west. The district champawat is the dynasty of chand rulers. They built lots of temples and ancient monuments in their ancient capital is champawat. So these monuments are the greatest attractions for the tourist peoples now days. Baleshwar, devidhura, pancheshwar, poornagiri temple are few such architectural building which built by the chand dynasty. The region has wide density of dark forests, which is a habitat center of millions of wild animals. Jim corbett//’s book, //“man eaters of kumaon\\” is merely related to the wild life that he sawed and experienced in champawat. According to the senses, champawat is the second least populous region in state of uttarakhand. Tehsils: barakot, champawat, lohaghat, pati, and purnagiri are the major places of champawat officially the region champawat was formed in 15 december 1997 by mayawati. The region is blessed with the extravagance of nature beauty; the contemporary development didn’t much demolish the beauty of the region. The site champawat is well connected by the roads with roads and world class hotels and resorts

\n\n\t\t Champawat district, geographically divided into terai, shivalik and high mountain ranges is widely appreciated as the origin of culture and religion in uttarakhand state. Varied in geography, champawat situates between 200-2000 meters above sea level experiencing different types of climate and weather in different heights. The beautiful region housing ancient temples and preserving original culture as part of life, champawat maintains its flavor in language, culture and tradition.



    </string>
    <string name="Pithoragarh">
        <b>Pithoragarh :: </b>
     \n\n\t\t   Pithoragarh District having its entire northern and eastern boundaries being international, assumes a great strategic significance and, obviously, is a politically sensitive district along the northern frontier of India. Being the last district adjoining Tibbet, it has tremendous strategic importance as the passes of Lipulekh, Kungribingri, Lampia Dhura, Lawe Dhura, Belcha and Keo, open out to Tibbet. The breath taking beauty of Pithoragarh – Himalayas, wide expenses of grassy meadow, perennial streams roaring down the zig-zag course, a stupendous variety of flora and fauna, above all, pure nature yet unsullied, seem to beckon the beholder into their folds, into a charmed world of virgin beauty.

\n\n\t\t It was in the wake of the Chinese aggression that on the 24th Feb. 1960, a sizeable section of Almora district was carved into Pithoragarh district containing extreme border areas with its head quarters in Pithoragarh town. On 15th September 1997, the Champawat Tehsil, hitherto under Pithoragarh, was carved into Champawat district.

\n\n\t\t The Pithoragarh town is located at a height of 1645 meters above sea level.The district lies between 29.4° to 30.3° North latitude and 80° to 81° East longitude along the eastern and southern part of the central Himalayas with Indo-Tibbetan watershed divide in the north and the Kali river.

forming a continuous border with Nepal  in  the  east. The Pithoragarh district   is  surrounded by the national  boundaries  of   Almora, Champawat,
Bageshwar and Chamoli districts and extends over  an area of  7,217.7  sq. Kms.  The details of  the land utilization are given as below :


        \n\n\t\t There are numerous scenic spots to which the prospective tourist may plan excursions like Chandak, Thal Kedar, Gangolihat (77 kms) famous for its kali temple, Patal Bhuvneshwar (99 kms) , Berinag (Tea Garden of Chaukori – 11 km away from Berinag), Didihat,Munsyari (base camp for traks to Milam,Ralam and Namik Glacier), Dharchula(base camp for Kailas Mansarover Yatra, Adi Kailash Yatra, Narayan Swami Ashram) and Jauljibi.
    </string>

    <string name="Nanital">
        <b>Nanital::</b>
      \n\n\t\t  Nainital is referred to in the \‘Manas Khand’ of the \‘Skanda Purana’ as the Tri-Rishi-Sarovar,the lake of the three sages ,Atri,Pulastya and Pulaha who were reputed to have arrived here on a penitential piligrimage, and, finding no water to quench their thirst dug a hole and siphoned water into it from Mansarovar the sacred lake in Tibet.

\n\n\t\t The Second important mythological reference to Nainital is as one of 64 \‘Shakti Peeths’.These centres were created wherever parts of charred body of Sati fell ,when Lord Shiva was carrying around her corpse in grief .It is said that the left eye (Nain) of Sati fell here and this gave rise to patron deity of town Nainital . It is said that the lake is formed in the emerald eye shape . Naina Devi temple is located at the northern end of the lake . Thus name of Nainital derivated from Naina and the tal (Lake).
    </string>

    <string name="Mussorie">
        <b>Musoorie ::</b>
       \n\n\t\t Mussoorie is a hill station and a municipal board, near Dehradun city in the Dehradun district of the Indian state of Uttarakhand. It is about 35 kilometres (22 mi) from the state capital of Dehradun and 290 km (180 mi) north of the national capital of New Delhi. The hill station is in the foothills of the Garhwal Himalayan range. The adjoining town of Landour, which includes a military cantonment, is considered part of \ "greater Mussoorie"\ , as are the townships of Barlowganj and Jharipani.[3]

  \n\n\t\t  Mussoorie is at an average altitude of 2,005 metres (6,578 ft). To the northeast are the Himalayan snow ranges, and to the south, the Doon Valley and Shiwalik ranges. The second highest point is the original Lal Tibba in Landour, with a height of over 2,275 m (7,464 ft). Mussoorie is popularly known as The Queen of the Hills.[4][5]

    </string>

    <string name = "Kedarnath">

        <b>Kedarnath</b>

    </string>

    <string name="JaswantSingh">
        <b> Riflemen JASWANTH SINGH </b>

 \n\n\t\t  Rifleman Jaswant Singh Rawat was born on 19 August 1941 to Shri Guman Singh Rawat, at village Baryun in Pauri Garhwal district of Uttarakhand. Rfn Jaswant Singh joined Indian Army on 19 Aug 1960 at the age of 19 years. He was recruited into 4 Garhwal Rifles of the famed Garhwal Rifles Regiment, known for its gallantry and many battle honours in various operations.  During 1962 Indo-China war, Rfn Jaswant Singh’s unit was deployed in the NEFA region.

      \n\n\t\t  When the troops of Garhwal Rifles were given the command to return back from Battle of Nuranang, a 21-year-old Sepoy from the unit refused to leave the battleground. In a display of rare courage, he held the post and gave a tough time to the Chinese soldiers with his dare-devilry. Rfn Jaswant Singh was martyred in the battle, but fought courageously for three days, and almost to the last man.

    </string>

    <string name ="Msdhoni">
        <b>Mahendra Singh Dhoni </b>

       \n\n\t\t Dhoni was born in Ranchi, Bihar (now in Jharkhand) and hails from a Hindu Rajput family with roots in Uttarakhand. He is the youngest of three children of Pan Singh and Devaki Devi. His paternal village Lwali, is in Jainti Tehsil, Lamgara block of the Almora District of Uttarakhand. His parents moved from Uttarakhand to Ranchi, Jharkhand where his father worked as a pump operator in junior management position in MECON Colony situated in Doranda area in Ranchi. Unlike Dhoni, his uncle and cousins spell their surname as Dhauni.

\n\n\t\t Previously Dhoni was the goalkeeper for his DAV Jawahar Vidya Mandir school\\\'s football team, but after seeing his goalkeeping skills, coach Keshav Ranjan Banerjee, one who inspired Dhoni to be a cricketer, picked him to play cricket for his school team.
        \n\n\t\t His exceptional wicketkeeping skills allowed him to become the regular wicketkeeper at the Commando Cricket Club (1995–1998). Based on his performance at club cricket, he was picked for the 1997/98 season Vinoo Mankad Trophy Under-16 Championship, where he performed well.

\n\n\t\t From 2001 to 2003, Dhoni worked as a Travelling Ticket Examiner (TTE) at Kharagpur railway station under South Eastern Railway in Midnapore (W), a district in West Bengal.

    </string>

    <string name = "Auli" >
        <b>Auli</b>

       \n\n\t\t Auli is in Chamoli district in the Himalayan mountains of Uttarakhand, India. Auli, also known as Auli Bugyal, in Garhwali, which means \"meadow"\, is located at an elevation of 2,800 metres (9,200 ft) above sea level. Between June and October, the valley has one of highest numbers of flower species found anywhere in the world, with 520 species of high altitude plants, 498 of which are flowering plants with significant populations of endangered species
    </string>

    <string name = "Badrinath">
        <b>Badrinath</b>

    </string>

    <string name = "Lohaghat">
        <b>Lohaghat</b>

        \n\n\t\t Lohaghat (Kumaoni: Loghāt) is a town and a nagar palika in Champawat district in the Indian state of Uttarakhand.
\n\n\t\t Lohaghat and its surrounding region was earlier known as Sui, and the town has been a place of prominence since the rule of Katyuri kings. A scion of the Katyuri dynasty had established his principality at Sui in the eighth century.[2] The rulers of Sui were feudatory to the Katyuris until the fragmentation of the Katyuri kingdom in the end of the 10th century, after which, they became feudatories of Doti.[3] Brahma Dev Katyuri, the last Katyuri governor of Sui was having trouble managing his areas due to several rebellions by local Khasia chiefs. The Khasia chiefs subsequently unified under a Raut king of Damkot thus increasing problems for Brahmadev, who married off his daughter to prince Somchand, and bestowed him with his principality as dowry.

    </string>


</resources>